Guide to the Forrest Gander Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Forrest Gander papers
1956-2006
1980-2006
YCAL MSS 765
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
25.09
(29 boxes)
Collection contains correspondence, writings, printed material, and other paper by or relating to American poet Forrest Gander. There is correspondence with other poets, writers, translators, and publishers. Correspondents include James Merrill, Robert Creeley, Clayton Eshleman, Rosmarie Waldrop, Fanny Howe, Ann Lauterbach, Michael Palmer, Michael Ondaatje, Marjorie Welish, David Shapiro, Mei-Mei Berssenbrugge, Charles Bernstein, Cole Swensen, Henri Cole, Peter Cole, Peter Gizzi, and many others. In addition to correspondence, there are writings by Gander and others, as well as material relating to translations and editorial projects, such as the Mouth to Mouth anthology on Mexican poetry, printed materials, such as publicity and reviews, and personal papers, including photographs and notebooks.
Gander, Forrest, 1956-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired by gift and purchase, 2007. For more information consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 12a and 27 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 28 (reel-to-reel tape): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Forrest Gander (1956-)
The author of numerous books of poetry, including Redstart: An Ecological Poetics and Science & Steepleflower, Gander is also the author of a novel ( As a Friend ), essays ( A Faithful Existence ) and translations. His poems appear in literary magazines in the United States and abroad, and his poems and books of poetry have been widely translated. His own translations include Watchword by Pura López Colomé, Spectacle & Pigsty by Kiwao Nomura, winner of the Best Translated Book Award, and Firefly Under the Tongue: Selected Poems of Coral Bracho, a finalist for the PEN Translation Prize. Other awards include a United States Artists Rockefeller Fellowhip and fellowships from The National Endowment for the Arts and the Guggenheim, Whiting, and Howard Foundations.
Gander was born in Barstow, California, grew up in Virginia, and spent significant periods of time in San Francisco, Dolores Hidalgo (Mexico), and Eureka Springs, Arkansas before moving to Rhode Island, where he is Adele Kellenberg Seaver Professor of Literary Arts and Comparative Literature at Brown University.
Biographical information taken from the author's website at <http://forrestgander.com/bio.html>.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence, writings, printed material, and other papers by or relating to American poet and translator Forrest Gander. The first January 2007 Acquisition consists chiefly of correspondence with other poets, writers, translators, and publishers. Correspondents include James Merrill, Robert Creeley, Clayton Eshleman, Rosmarie Waldrop, Fanny Howe, Ann Lauterbach, Michael Palmer, Michael Ondaatje, Marjorie Welish, David Shapiro, Mei-Mei Berssenbrugger, Charles Bernstein, Cole Swenson, Henri Cole, Peter Cole, Peter Gizzi, and many others. The second January 2007 Acquisition contains additional correspondence, writings by Gander and others, as well as material relating to translations and editorial projects, such as the Mouth to Mouth anthology on Mexican poetry, printed materials, such as publicity and reviews, and personal papers, including photographs and notebooks.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: January 2007 Acquisition and January 2007 Acquisition.
American literature -- 20th Century; Mexican poetry -- 20th Century; Mexican poetry -- Translations into English; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Born digital; Electronic documents; Photographic prints; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Bernstein, Charles, 1950-; Berssenbrugge, Mei-mei, 1947-; Cole, Henri, 1956-; Cole, Peter, 1957-; Creeley, Robert, 1926-2005; Eshleman, Clayton; Gander, Forrest, 1956-; Gizzi, Peter, 1959-; Howe, Fanny, 1940-; Lauterbach, Ann, 1942-; Merrill, James, 1926-1995; Ondaatje, Michael, 1943-; Palmer, Michael, 1943-; Shapiro, David, 1947-; Swensen, Cole, 1955-; Waldrop, Rosmarie, 1935-; Welish, Marjorie, 1944-
- January 2007 Acquisition, 1969-2006; 11.63; (13 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 12a (computer disks): Restricted Fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically and then alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  The first January 2007 Acquisition consists chiefly of correspondence with other poets, writers, translators, and publishers. Correspondents include James Merrill, Robert Creeley, Clayton Eshleman, Rosmarie Waldrop, Fanny Howe, Ann Lauterbach, Michael Palmer, Michael Ondaatje, Marjorie Welish, David Shapiro, Mei-Mei Berssenbrugger, Charles Bernstein, Cole Swenson, Henri Cole, Peter Cole, Peter Gizzi, and many others.
  Printed lists of correspondents and writings can be found in some folders.
  Former call numbers: Uncat MSS 937.
  Gift of Forrest Gander and C. D. Wright, 2007.
  - 1987-1992, undated, 3 (Box 1)
  - 1989, 1969-1990, undated (Box 1)
  - 1990, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - 1993, 1991-1994, undated; 6 (Box 1)
  - 1994, 1993-1994; 6 (Box 1)
  - 1994, 1993-1994; 4 (Box 2)
  - 1994-1995, undated, 2 (Box 2)
  - 1995, 1987-1995; 8 (Box 2)
  - 1993-1996, undated, 8 (Box 3)
  - 1996, 1993-1996, undated; 7 (Box 3)
  - 1996, 1995-1996; 3 (Box 4)
  - 1997, 1995-1997, undated; 13 (Box 4)
  - 1997, 1995-1997, undated; 3 (Box 5)
  - 1997-1998, undated, 4 (Box 5)
  - 1998, 1997-1998; 8 (Box 5)
  - 1998, 1997-1999; 12 (Box 6)
  - 1999, 1998-1999; 4 (Box 6)
  - 1999, 1996-1999, undated; 8 (Box 7)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 7)
  - 2000, 1999-2000; 8 (Box 7)
  - 2000, 1998-2000; 6 (Box 8)
  - 2000-2001, undated (Box 8)
  - 2001, 2000-2001; 12 (Box 8)
  - Computer files, circa 1998-2001; (5 computer disks) (Box 8)
    Computer disks are restricted. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    2007-ycal-13601-0001: Harvard 99-00, Harvard 00-01
    2007-ycal-13601-0002: 1999-2000 laptop files, Harvard Brown letters
    2007-ycal-13601-0003: Spring 2000 laptop, Harvard Brown letters Rees
    2007-ycal-13601-0004: Mule, 9/03/98
    2007-ycal-13601-0005: 1/99 Backup disk, poetry and translation
  - 2001-2002, 2 (Box 9)
  - 2002, 2000-2002, undated; 6 (Box 9)
  - 2003, 2003-2004; 4 (Box 9)
  - 2004, 2003-2004; 3 (Box 9)
  - 2004, 2002-2004; 2 (Box 10)
  - 2000-2004, undated, 3 (Box 10)
  - 2005, 2 (Box 10)
  - 2006, 2005-2006, undated; 6 (Box 10)
  - Duffy, Tom, 1980-1993, undated; 2 (Box 10)
  - Earnhart, Brady, 1992-1993, undated (Box 11)
  - Gizzi, Peter, undated (Box 11)
  - High, Jon, 1988-1991, undated (Box 11)
  - Junghans, Lida, 1980-1993, undated; 4 (Box 11)
  - Ortega, Julio, 1989-1991, undated (Box 11)
  - Sato, Hiro, 1994, undated (Box 11)
  - Swensen, Cole, 1990-1993, undated (Box 11)
  - Editors, 1983-1992, undated (Box 11)
  - Correspondence relating to personal history, 1980-1992, undated; 2 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1991-1993, undated (Box 11)
  - Gamblin, Noriko, 1975-1980, undated; 4 (Box 12)
  - Kameoka, Yuko, 1978-1982, undated; 3 (Box 12)
  - Letters to others, 1982-1988, undated (Box 12)
  - Computer media
    Box 12a (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - HARVARD 99-00 HARVARD 00-01, 2007-ycal-13601-0001; 1 (Box 12a)
      Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - 1999-2000 Laptop Files Harvard Brown Letters, 2007-ycal-13601-0002; 1 (Box 12a)
    - Spring 2000 Laptop Harvard Brown Letters Recs, 2007-ycal-13601-0003; 1 (Box 12a)
    - Mule 9/03/98 Forrest GANDER 401 245 8069, 2007-ycal-13601-0004; 1 (Box 12a)
    - 1/99 Back-up Disk Poetry Translation 4-99, 2007-ycal-13601-0005; 1 (Box 12a)
- January 2007 Acquisition, 1956-2006; 13.46; (15 boxes)
  Box 27 (computer disks): Restricted Fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 28 (reel-to-reel tape): Restricted Fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Files are not arranged in any particular order.
  This second January 2007 Acquisition contains additional correspondence, writings by Gander and others, as well as material relating to translations and editorial projects, such as the Mouth to Mouth anthology on Mexican poetry, printed materials, such as publicity and reviews, and personal papers, including photographs and notebooks.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 937.
  Purchased from Lame Duck Books on various funds, 2007.
  - Drafts of "Arrows", 1996-1997; 10 (Box 13)
  - Drawing, 1975 (Box 13)
  - "Battlefield Where the Moon Says I Love You," Lost Roads editorial work, 2000; 15 (Box 14)
  - "Battlefield Where the Moon Says I Love You," Lost Roads editorial work, undated; 7 (Box 15)
  - Poems by Gerardo Deniz, Lost Roads editorial work, 1995-2000, undated; 2 (Box 15)
  - Science and Steepleflower, 1997; 2 (Box 15)
  - "Science and the Incantation of Matter", undated; 2 (Box 15)
  - Poems from Providence College, undated (Box 15)
  - Poems, drafts, 1997, undated; 3 (Box 15)
  - "Durable Fire", 199?-2000, undated; 4 (Box 15)
  - "Vagabonds", undated (Box 16)
  - Photocopies of reviews, 1996-2000, undated (Box 16)
  - Reviews of Science and Steepleflower, 1997-1999, undated (Box 16)
  - Reviews of Lynchburg, 1993, undated (Box 16)
  - Publicity, 1987-1997, undated; 4 (Box 16)
  - Rejection notices, 1981-1996; 2 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with New Directions, 1980-1998, undated; 2 (Box 16)
  - Book promotion, 1994 (Box 16)
  - "Deeds," reviews, 1994-1996, undated (Box 16)
  - "Deeds," tip sheets and New England envelopes, 1993, undated (Box 16)
  - Wesleyan, 1992-1999 (Box 16)
  - Editorial correspondence re "Deeds", 1990 (Box 16)
  - Pittsburg, 1991-2000, undated; 3 (Box 16)
  - Milkweed, 1990-1998, undated (Box 16)
  - Trans(lations), 1994 August 11 (Box 16)
  - "England and Lotus Root", 1991-1992, undated (Box 16)
  - Rush to the Lake, 1984-1989, undated (Box 16)
  - Alice James books, undated (Box 16)
  - Performance catalogs, 1985-1991; 2 (Box 17)
  - Editorial and other projects, 1983-1984, undated; 2 (Box 17)
  - Juvenilia writing, notebook and sketches, 1979, undated; 2 (Box 17)
  - Juvenilia, "Chaff poem", undated (Box 17)
  - Juvenilia, "Swarm", undated (Box 17)
  - Juvenilia, "Hurricane", undated (Box 17)
  - Juvenilia, "Atavism", undated (Box 17)
  - Magazine submission file, undated; 2 (Box 17)
  - Recommendations, 1984-1992, undated (Box 17)
  - Publicity, 1986-1993, undated; 2 (Box 17)
  - Publicity photos, undated (Box 17)
  - Saenz, drafts, 1998-2000, undated; 3 (Box 17)
  - Colome, Pura Lopez - finished translations, 1999 (Box 17)
  - Colome, Pura Lopez, 1999, undated; 2 (Box 17)
  - Colome, Pura Lopez - notes, 1999 (Box 17)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence, 1990-1992, undated; 2 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Janet Rodney, 1987-1990 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Steve Tapscott, 1988, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Carolyn Forche, 1984-1986, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Thomas Hoeksema, 1990, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Jenny Goodman, 1989, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Patricia Goedicke, 1986-1988 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Martina Christina, 1983-1986 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Rocio Aragon, 1985-1987 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Lida Aronne-Amestay, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - W. S. Merwin, 1984-1985, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Maureen Ahern, 1983-1984, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Jason Weiss, 1984-1990, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Anne Honestein Sylvia Madrigal, 1984-1992 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Carmen Boullosa, 1983-1993, undated; 2 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Coral Bracha, 1990 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Elsa Cross, 1987-1993 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Isabel Fraire, 1987-1991 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Kyra Galvan, 1984-1988, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Gloria Gervitz, 1984-1991, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Elva Macias, 1984-1993 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Monica Mansour, 1984-1986, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Elena Milan, 1984-1986, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Myriam Moscona, 1987, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Enriqueta Ochoa, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Isabel Quinoz, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Silvia Tomasa Rivera, 1987, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Veronica Volkow, 1981-1987 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - Esther Seligson, 1982-1984 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence- Zoe Anglesey, 1987-1992, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth correspondence - general, 1981-1991 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth - Mexican poets project notes re publication, 1982-1991 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth - administrative, 1987-1991 (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth - poems in the original, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth - permissions, 1990-1991 (Box 18)
  - Vuelta magazine, 1982-1987 (Box 18)
  - Mexican Poets - Alejandro Aura, undated (Box 18)
  - Mexican Poets - Carmen Boullosa, undated (Box 18)
  - Mexican Poets - Coral Bracho, undated (Box 18)
  - Mexican Poets - Isabel Fiore, undated (Box 18)
  - Mexican Poets - Nina Iskrenko, undated (Box 18)
  - Mexican Poets - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 18)
  - Mexican Poets - Tamura Ryuichi, undated (Box 18)
  - Translation notes, undated (Box 18)
  - Mouth to Mouth, 1991-1995, undated; 6 (Box 19)
  - Review: Latin America Literature and Arts, 1990 (Box 19)
  - Mouth to Mouth - original translations by Americans, 1983-1987, undated (Box 19)
  - Photos and responses - Mexico, 1984-1990, undated (Box 19)
  - Mouth to Mouth - works in manuscripts, 1987, undated; 2 (Box 19)
  - Mouth to Mouth - American translations, undated; 2 (Box 19)
  - Mouth to Mouth - original TS, undated (Box 19)
  - Mouth to Mouth - TS, undated; 2 (Box 19)
  - Diary pages, 1965-1966 (Box 20)
  - Notebooks, 1985-1994; 19 (Box 20)
  - Notebooks, 1980-2004; 10 (Box 21)
  - Calendar, 1987 (Box 21)
  - S.F. State M.A. thesis, 1981 August (Box 21)
  - Megacycles 89, 1978 December (Box 21)
  - "The Light the Dead See'", undated (Box 21)
  - Notebooks and diaries, 1979-1987; 4 (Box 21)
  - Notebooks, 1995-2000; 12 (Box 22)
  - Jorie Graham manuscripts, 2001, undated; 4 (Box 22)
  - Super 8 film: A Death in the Family, 1987 August 25 (Box 23)
  - My mother's notes on me since infancy, 1956-1973 (Box 23)
  - Letters from Brady Earnhart, 1978-1980; 2 (Box 23)
  - James Agee, David Plante lectures, 1987, undated (Box 23)
  - Proofs for Eye Against Eye, with corrections, 2005 July (Box 23)
  - Immanent Visitor, poems of Jaime Saenz, undated (Box 23)
  - 8-18 Saenz, 2000, undated (Box 23)
  - Immanent Visitor, undated (Box 23)
  - Corresp(ondence): Leonardo Garcia Pabon, 2001 June (Box 23)
  - Saenz -- Immanent Visitor misc., 2001-2004, undated (Box 23)
  - MS of various essays that became A Faithful Existence, 2003, undated (Box 23)
  - Notes: Misc. '01-03, 1996-2003, undated (Box 23)
  - MS of Rush to the Lake, undated (Box 23)
  - Notes, drafts, outtakes, 2003-2004, undated (Box 23)
  - School papers, 1970, undated (Box 24)
  - Notebooks, undated; 4 (Box 24)
  - College papers, undated (Box 24)
  - School report cards, etc., 1956-1987, undated (Box 24)
  - HS Yearbook, 1974 (Box 24)
  - Reviews, 1989-1994, undated (Box 24)
  - Unidentified manuscript, undated (Box 24)
  - Essays, 1989-1996, undated (Box 24)
  - Essays - images, undated (Box 24)
  - List of box contents, undated (Box 25)
  - Amestoy, 1989-1999, undated; 5; (1 computer disk) (Box 25)
    2007-ycal-4687-0075: Lida's translations
  - Miscellaneous, 1993-1994, undated (Box 25)
  - To/from Moscow, 1989-1993, undated (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1990-1993, undated (Box 25)
  - Trans(lation) project, 1986-1993, undated; 16 (Box 25)
  - Russian doll pen, undated (Box 25)
  - Publicity/Russian, 1984-1994, undated (Box 25)
  - Moscow translations of Forrest Gander by Nina Iskenko, 1984 (Box 25)
  - Photographs, undated; 10 (Box 25)
  - Envelope, undated (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1995-2006, undated (Box 25)
  - Oversize
    - Printed poems, undated (Box 26)
    - Notebooks, 1995, undated; 3 (Box 26)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 26)
  - Computer media and audiovisual materials
    Restricted fragile material. Access copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Computer disks (from box 25), circa 1993-2002; (69 computer disks)
      2007-ycal-4687-0006 - 2007-ycal-4687-0075
      Box 27 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Letters 1998 #3 of 3, 2007-ycal-4687-0006; 1 (Box 27)
      - Letters 1998 #2 of 3, 2007-ycal-4687-0007; 1 (Box 27)
      - Letters 1998 #1 of 3, 2007-ycal-4687-0008; 1 (Box 27)
      - Essays Bidart's Desire, Creeley: Life & Death, Yasusada: Double F | Reviews Nymph Stick Translation: Whole, 2007-ycal-4687-0009; 1 (Box 27)
      - New Directions 11/97 --, 2007-ycal-4687-0010; 1 (Box 27)
      - EARLIER MSS OF SCIENCE & POEMS 97-98 Science & Steeple Flower 10/10/97, 2007-ycal-4687-0011; 1 (Box 27)
      - TRAVELING DISK FORREST GANDER 401-247-0819, 2007-ycal-4687-0012; 1 (Box 27)
      - Poems 95-96, 2007-ycal-4687-0013; 1 (Box 27)
      - Translations 5-4-99, 6-11-99, 2007-ycal-4687-0014; 1 (Box 27)
      - Translations, 2007-ycal-4687-0015; 1 (Box 27)
      - Frank Stanford Battlefield Back-up disc, 2007-ycal-4687-0016; 1 (Box 27)
      - VITA 8/26/96 11/26/96, 2007-ycal-4687-0017; 1 (Box 27)
      - Presses / Marketing 1994-, 2007-ycal-4687-0018; 1 (Box 27)
      - Letters 1993-1994 June, 2007-ycal-4687-0019; 1 (Box 27)
      - WESLEYAN, 2007-ycal-4687-0020; 1 (Box 27)
      - MILKWEED ED, 2007-ycal-4687-0021; 1 (Box 27)
      - PITTSBURGH PITTSBURGH PRESS Pittsburgh, 2007-ycal-4687-0022; 1 (Box 27)
      - Forrest / Working Files 2 / '94 Essays, Poems, Fiction, 2007-ycal-4687-0023; 1 (Box 27)
      - 8/02/92 Arrows Past 1 (1-6) 11/08/93 ARROWS BACK UP (HOUSE CITY) 11/24/93 5/02/94, 2007-ycal-4687-0024; 1 (Box 27)
      - Forrest / Working Files / '94 Notes, letters, 2007-ycal-4687-0025; 1 (Box 27)
      - 1996 Summer VCCA, 2007-ycal-4687-0026; 1 (Box 27)
      - ARROWS 1995 5/17/96 SE, 2007-ycal-4687-0027; 1 (Box 27)
      - ARROWS 1/02/94 UPDATED FEB 01 1995 PERFORMA VERSION, 2007-ycal-4687-0028; 1 (Box 27)
      - ARROWS SEPT 1995 Forrest Gander 10/09/96 319-351-8177, 2007-ycal-4687-0029; 1 (Box 27)
      - Science & Steeple Flower version #1 Ingenium; Marriage & Poems 1993-1997 8/31/97, 2007-ycal-4687-0030; 1 (Box 27)
      - Currier 2, 1997-, 2007-ycal-4687-0031; 1 (Box 27)
      - 1987 Taxes CURRIER 3, 1995 COMPATABLE W/ SE, 2007-ycal-4687-0032; 1 (Box 27)
      - POEMS Science & Mystery 8/28/96 Science & In[illegible] Light 10/13/96, 2007-ycal-4687-0033; 1 (Box 27)
      - Poems 5.1a 1993-1994-1995 BACK-UP, 2007-ycal-4687-0034; 1 (Box 27)
      - LETTERS JUNE 1994 - MAY 1996 SE BACK UP 5/17/96, 2007-ycal-4687-0035; 1 (Box 27)
      - TRANSLATIONS TRANSLATION 1995- BACK-UP 5/17/96, 2007-ycal-4687-0036; 1 (Box 27)
      - Poems 95-96 BACK UP 5/17/96, 2007-ycal-4687-0037; 1 (Box 27)
      - Essays 1994- dark end of street, Influorescence Verity BACK-UP 5/17/96, 2007-ycal-4687-0038; 1 (Box 27)
      - ARROWS November 1994- BACK-UP, 2007-ycal-4687-0039; 1 (Box 27)
      - POETRY 1996 Poetry 5/93-5/96 BACK-UP, 2007-ycal-4687-0040; 1 (Box 27)
      - Applications Guggenheim '93 BACK UP 5/17/96, 2007-ycal-4687-0041; 1 (Box 27)
      - PCOLLEGE Providence College VITA Essays: Application, Moscow BACK UP 5/17/96, 2007-ycal-4687-0042; 1 (Box 27)
      - Fictions HOUSE MULE 1996 BACK UP 5/17/96, 2007-ycal-4687-0043; 1 (Box 27)
      - Master Disk Copy Microsoft Word Program Disk, 2007-ycal-4687-0044; 1 (Box 27)
      - Arrows Christmas '94 #1 1/02/95, 2007-ycal-4687-0045; 1 (Box 27)
      - CURRIER 1 Vita / Resume Essays Nymph Stick Insect Critical Response to Bourke by FG, 2007-ycal-4687-0046; 1 (Box 27)
      - ARROW January 03 1995 p. 111 Feb 01, 2007-ycal-4687-0047; 1 (Box 27)
      - August 1993 / ARROWS / NEW DRAFT 11/24/93 1/05/93 5/02/94, 2007-ycal-4687-0048; 1 (Box 27)
      - MISCELLANEOUS 1996- Applications / Awards Submissions Job Applications Mutual Fund Portfolio, 2007-ycal-4687-0049; 1 (Box 27)
      - PRACTICE poems / fictions / Correspondence Notes, 2007-ycal-4687-0050; 1 (Box 27)
      - Reviews 11/26/96, 2007-ycal-4687-0051; 1 (Box 27)
      - ESSAYS to 5/17/96 SE, 2007-ycal-4687-0052; 1 (Box 27)
      - TRANSLATION 9/02/94, 2007-ycal-4687-0053; 1 (Box 27)
      - TRANSLATION 9/02/94 - BACK-UP, 2007-ycal-4687-0054; 1 (Box 27)
      - MAC FILES 1996-97 Reviews, Essays, Translations, e-mail cleared from Mac 3/99, 2007-ycal-4687-0055; 1 (Box 27)
      - LETTERS LETRES LETTERS to '93, 2007-ycal-4687-0056; 1 (Box 27)
      - LOST ROADS LOST ROADS LOST ROADS FANNY HOWE'S THE VINEYARD, 2007-ycal-4687-0057; 1 (Box 27)
      - Snake Sucking Egg 4/01/97, 2007-ycal-4687-0058; 1 (Box 27)
      - MAC 5/03/97 Major Files Science Steepleflower Poem Snake Sucking Egg, 2007-ycal-4687-0059; 1 (Box 27)
      - Science Steepleflower versions #2 & Poems 1993-1997 4/01/87 8/21/97, 2007-ycal-4687-0060; 1 (Box 27)
      - Science & Steepleflower 10/09/97 Saved for Macscience Forrest Gander / NEW DIRECTIONS MAC DISC, 2007-ycal-4687-0061; 1 (Box 27)
      - Poetry Mac 636 95-98, 2007-ycal-4687-0062; 1 (Box 27)
      - Letters 5/97-8/98, 2007-ycal-4687-0063; 1 (Box 27)
      - Letters (Iowa) 8/08/96 -- 11/26/96, 2007-ycal-4687-0064; 1 (Box 27)
      - FORREST LETTERS 94-96 From B's MAC, 2007-ycal-4687-0065; 1 (Box 27)
      - LETTERS 6/94 - 5/96 SE, 2007-ycal-4687-0066; 1 (Box 27)
      - TRANSLATION 9/02/94 - 5/17/96 SE, 2007-ycal-4687-0067; 1 (Box 27)
      - DC LETTERS Sept. 1994 - 5/17/96 PC, 2007-ycal-4687-0068; 1 (Box 27)
      - Forrest 1995 Perfume 575 Miscellaneous from B's Mac, 2007-ycal-4687-0069; 1 (Box 27)
      - MISCELLANEOUS FROM SE 1) VITA 2) AWARD / FELLOWSHIP APPLICATIONS 3) BOOKS & PRESSES 4) PUBLISHING, 2007-ycal-4687-0070; 1 (Box 27)
      - MISCELLANEOUS #2 from SE 1) LOST ROADS 2) OTHER BUSINESS, 2007-ycal-4687-0071; 1 (Box 27)
      - POEMS 93-96 5/17/96 SE, 2007-ycal-4687-0072; 1 (Box 27)
      - 3/25/98 MAC...DISK [illegible] Essay / Yasusada review, 2007-ycal-4687-0073; 1 (Box 27)
      - LETTERS 1997, 2007-ycal-4687-0074; 1 (Box 27)
      - LIDA's TRANSLATIONS, 2007-ycal-4687-0075; 1 (Box 27)
    - Super 8 film: A Death in the Family (Box 28)
      Box 28 (reel-to-reel tape): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.